本字幕由 ShinY 深影字幕组 原创翻译制作
深影字幕组论坛地址 http://shinybbs.com
翻译： 王老猫 JoJo Vernie fanfan Shirley
校对： 小坏玩意儿   后期： 泡面君
《隧道谜案》前情提要
你杀了迈赫迪 你这个杂种
警察杀了他 而你呢
表现得就像他们碾死了你的狗
实验室
The labs
拿到了博蒙特笔记本里的数据
were able to get back the data from Beaumont's laptop.
看看他们找到了什么
And look what they found.
真理杀手的第一个受害者
TT's first victim on Beaumont's computer .
把他带过来
Bring him in.
没人能强迫你杀一个孩子
我只是遵照命令
打扰一下
需要帮忙吗 女士
我丈夫失踪了
您需要先在前台登记
不能直接这么进来
水龙头还开着
我们昨晚谈了谈
然后我去睡觉了
今早他就不见了
我给他的同事打了电话 但是没人知道他在哪
您是怎么通过前台的
求你了
呆在这 我们会处理的
请自便
Help yourself.
和爱丽丝怎么样了
Well... so how's it going with Elise?
- 什么怎么样 - 一起工作啊
- How is what going with Elise? - Working together.
我们合作很愉快
We're working fine together.
她单身吗
Is she single?
告诉我你在开玩笑
Tell me you are joking!
怎么了 跟你相比她和我年龄更接近
What? She is nearer my age than yours.
我不想跟你讨论她是否单身的问题
I'm not arguing if she is single.
跟你说 我一会儿会见到她
Tell you what I'm seeing her in a minute
我会告诉她 她有了个爱慕者
I'll tell her she has got an admirer.
把你房间整理了
Tidy your room.
苏
Suze.
停车场有辆红色高尔夫
There is a red Golf in the car park.
钥匙在你包里
The key is in your bag.
杂物箱里
In the glove box,
有些钱 可以供你生活
you'll find some money to keep you going.
怎么了
Why?
发生什么事了
What's happened?
告诉我
Tell me.
我再跟你说说那个游泳池吧
Let me tell you about the pool again.
还记得吗
Do you remember?
我们每个冬天都把里面的水抽干
We emptied it every winter.
你推了他
You push him.
我梦到了
I dream it.
每次都是你把那个畜生推下去
And every time you shoved the bastard in
他的头撞到了泳池底部
He smashed his head on the bottom.
然后他抬头看我
He looked up at me.
跟我说说他眼中的神情
Tell me about the expression in his eyes.
很挫败
Defeat.
他输了 我们赢了
He lost, we won.
我来就是想跟你说这个
That's what I came to tell you.
发生这些事以后
After everything that happened,
一切都会好的
it's all is going to be OK.
没人能伤害你了
Nobody will hurt you.
# 到我怀里来 #
Venez dans mes bras
# 靠近我 亲爱的 #
Closer to me, dear
# 让我自己 #
Donnez-vous moi
# 抛开所有恐惧 #
Set aside all fear
# 一根红线 缠绕永远 #
Restons enlaces pour l'ternit
# 是的 你是我的 #
Yes, you shall be mine
# 直到地老天荒 #
Till the end of time
《隧道谜案》第一季第六集
斯蒂芬・博蒙特呢
Where is Stephen Beaumont?
没见到他
I haven't seen him.
虽然都是间接证据
The evidence remains circumstantial,
但这个人肯定有问题
but there is something wrong with him.
听着 伙计们 警员去了苏的公寓
Hey, listen up guys. Uniforms were sent to Suzy's flat
没人应门
Nobody answered the door,
邻居说没见到她
and neighbors say they haven't seen her.
因为她在医院
Because she is in the hospital.
但是前晚他们听到
But there was some noise
房间里有声音
coming from there the night before last,
好像有人在打斗
some kind of fight or a struggle going on.
很整洁
Very tidy.
不像是大斗一场过
Not exactly rumble in the jungle.
有人清理干净了
Somebody has been cleaning up.
所以 要么是没打斗过
So either there was no fight,
要么就是非常惨烈
or it got much more serious.
上次 这幅画不在这儿
This picture wasn't here last time.
在的 我看见了
Yes it was, I saw it.
不 你看到时 是挂在那边的
No, when you saw it, it was hanging over there.
保持原样 这可能是犯罪现场
Stay there, we could have a crime scene.
安东尼・沃尔什 那个皮条客
Anthony Walsh, the pimp.
清洁工刚发现了他的尸体
Bin men just found his body.
他的头部受了重伤
He has his head quite seriously re-arranged.
让法医来这
Get forensics down here.
我们也许刚刚有了关键性证据
We may have just moved beyond the circumstantial.
什么时候
At what time?
天啊
Christ!
有人可能看到斯蒂芬・博蒙特在多佛港口
Possible sighting of Stethen Beaumont on a ferry at Dover.
我们过去
We'll get down there
并且要从边境控制那得到确认
and get confirmation from border control.
禁止他离开了吗?
Departure is prevented?
没有 我们警告过他
No, we'd alert him.
警察 我们要上去
Police. We get on this.
我们在那边有加莱提供的武装反应部队
We have Calais provide armed response unit at other end.
警方呼吁大家帮助
Police are appealing for help
寻找一名在福克斯通夜晚发生的凶杀案嫌犯
in finding a man they want to question over a murder
警方宣称斯蒂芬・博蒙特...
in Folkestone overnight. Police say Stephen Beaumont...
没事了
Okay.
你该和我们谈谈
You need to talk to us.
谈什么?
About what?
吉玛・柯万 还有其他事
Gemma Kirwan, among other things.
还有其他事
Among other things?
你认为是我杀了吉玛?
You think I'm the person who killed Gemma?
为什么你的电脑上有她的照片?
Why is her photo on your computer?
我只是记录下来我帮过的人
I keep records of people I help.
像安东尼・沃尔什?
Like Anthony Walsh?
他只是一心要破坏
He was just trying to destroy
我的工作
my work.
他对她做了同样的事
He was doing the same to her.
对谁?
To who?
我妹妹
My sister.
她又从我这溜走了
She was slipping away from me again.
把你的双手放到我们能看到的地方 斯蒂芬
Put your hands where we can see them, Steven.
我要把你作为嫌犯逮捕...
I am arresting you on suspicion...
我这有你可以上明天头版的消息
I have something for tomorrow's front page.
- 你还真是慷慨 - 它必须要在头版
- That is very generous of you. - It must be front page.
那可不是我说了算
That's not really my call.
再说现在也太早了些
Besides it's still early.
干新闻这行可不要计划地过早
Doesn't do to plan too far ahead.
你能明白我的意思吗?
when you work news, If you know what I mean?
我们鄙视这些年轻人
We hold the young in contempt.
那样对吗? 陶德
Is that right? Todd.
去年在英国有四分之一的被捕者
A quarter of those arrested in the UK last year
都在十八岁以下
were under 18.
都是年轻人惹的祸 我真是心痛
Hurt done by hoodies. My heart bleeds.
你在办公桌前吗?
Are you at your desk?
我在
I might be.
当下的年轻人
这个社会对年轻人总是不予理睬
Society turns its back on the young.
使得他们缺少关注
Makes them invisible.
你要从我选的里面挑出一个
You will put the ones I have selected
登在明天的头版
on tomorrow's front page.
让人们都能看到
Where people can see them.
真理杀手把他的第四条真理
TT posted his fourth truth
宣布在这个渡轮上死掉的
as Stephen Beaumont's life.
斯蒂芬・博蒙特身上
was slipping away on the ferry.
他究竟是谁?
Who was he really?
只是另一个觉得自己
Just another sad guy who thought
能改变世界的伤心人
he could change the world.
那纵火案呢?
And the burning?
真理杀手宣称他的真理叫"当下的年轻人"
TT is calling his truth "The youth of today."
他强调司法体系对现在的年轻人是该正确对待
He's highlighting the way the youth is treated or
还是虐待
mistreated by the justice system.
他努力想要被认可...
He was trying to get qualified...
想找到工作 想要被表扬...
trying to get a job, trying to get on...
但是这太难了 所以...
It's just so hard, so...
他说"我爱你 妈妈"然后就离开了
He said "I love you, Mom" and he was out the door.
那是我最后一次见他
That's the last time I saw him.
迪恩・阿特金森 十九岁
Dean Atkinson, 19.
因参与伦敦暴乱坐了两年牢
Did two years for his part in London riot.
不同于我们之前遇到过的任何烧伤
Quite unlike any burns we have come across.
我们偶尔也遇到过大面积扩散的
We occasionally get them as wide spread,
但从未像这样被严重腐蚀的
but never this corrosive.
所用的化学燃料
The chemical used,
我们认为应该是白磷
white phosphorus we think
毁掉了他百分之九十的皮肤
has taken off 90% of the skin.
烧伤最严重的部位是这儿还有这儿
The burns are most at their most intense here and here.
应该是有人把它装进了他的口袋里
Could one have been stuffed in his pockets.
他的衣服现在在哪?
Where are his clothes now ?
这就是我为什么说腐蚀的严重
That's what I meant by corrosive.
除了他的鞋和剩下的一部分织物
Apart from his shoes and the odd strand of fabric,
他几乎和他来的时候一样
he was nigh this when he came in.
磷是怎么被引燃的?
How did the phosphorus catch fire ?
需要好几分钟时间
Takes a good few minutes,
但是白磷一接触氧气就会变成燃烧得
but white phosphorus combusts on exposure to oxygen
更加猛烈的东西
becoming something far nastier,
叫做五氧化二磷
something called phosphorus pentoxide.
他家人来过了吗?
The family been here ?
他母亲要求过
His mother has been asking.
她不能看到这个
She can't see this.
她有权利
She has the right.
她是有 那我们就要阻止她行使权力
She does, and we have to  prevent her from exercising it.
又有三起纵火案
Three more burnings
都是男性青年 都是被定过罪的暴乱参与者
all male youths, all convicted roiters.
纵火都在公共场所 受害人都在几秒钟内死亡
All burned in public places  and dead within seconds.
不仅仅是公共场所
Public places isn't the half of it,
现在都成了电视节目的热点
these are CCTV hotspots.
他要的是最大可见度
He is after maximum visibility.
几乎变成道德信标了
Going up like moral beacons.
还是白磷?
White phosphorus again?
前两起是 第三起还在化验中
The first two, the lab is still checking on the 3rd.
为什么不在网上登出来?
Why isn't the web site up ?
你整天都在干什么?
What are you doing all day?
让我瞧瞧...
Here we go...
警察殴打 错误的抓捕
Police beating, wrongfully arrested
错误的判决
Disproportionate sentencing.
这是什么?
What's this?
这些是他为真理做的海报男孩
So these are the poster boys for his campaign.
下一步是什么
What next?
下一步
Next?
他做够了吗
Hasn't he done enough ?
让人去把四个网点的监控录像全部找来
Get uniforms to seize all CCTV footage of all four sites.
检查名单上所有的人
Run checks on all the names on that list.
我们明天要在加莱见面
We should meet in Calais tomorrow.
为什么 他们都是英国人
Why? They're all British.
海报男孩是来自两边的人
The poster boys are from both sides of the channel.
为什么要看法国年轻人
Why show French youth
如果你只是想烧死英国人
if you are only going to burn British?
我会叫塞西尔花一个晚上
I'll ask Cicile to spend the night
去调查我们这边的人
researching the ones from our side.
我要去喝一杯
I am off for a drink.
- 我今晚不行 抱歉 - 别害怕 伙计
- I can't tonight mate, sorry. - Don't panic, mate.
我没有邀请你
I am telling you  Not inviting you.
我把最终拷贝发邮件给你
I emailed through the final copy.
这个故事是烧死青年
The story was the burning youths!
不是...每个人都跟着那个
Nah... see everyone's running with that.
我们的故事是
For us the story is
真理杀手怎样试图告诉我们做什么
how TT tried to tell us what to do
以及我们是如何拒绝的
and how we refused.
继续干 好伙计
Keep up, chummy mate.
你为什么不带爱丽丝
Why didn't you take Elise?
什么
What?
你去夏洛特・鲁伯特家的时候
When you went back to Charlotte Joubert's house.
你为什么不带爱丽丝
Why didn't you take Elise?
因为夏洛特找的是我
Because Charlotte asked for me.
她也找你
And she asked for you.
总之 你自己也看到了
Anyway, you saw yourself,
爱丽丝在人堆里有一点笨手笨脚
Elise can be a bit clumsy around people.
想清楚
Make up your mind.
是因为夏洛特让你去
Is it because Charlotte asked you
还是因为爱丽丝在人堆里笨手笨脚
or because Elise can be clumsy around people
或者你这是在给我找借口
Or are you just throwing excuses my way,
希望我能相信
hoping one will stick.
你跟她上床了吗
Did you sleep with her?
天哪 天哪
God. Oh god.
我怀孕了
I'm pregnant for fuck's sake.
对不起
I'm sorry.
出去
Get out.
有人吗
我杀了你弟弟
究竟发生了什么
你想怎样
谁带你来这儿的
不是你吗
你得帮我
趁他没回来我们快走
是你杀了我弟弟吗
- 你是迈赫迪・谢尔菲的哥哥 - 闭嘴
不要说他的名字
你在干嘛
你这是干嘛
等一下
你想一下
听我说
我要你承认杀了我弟弟
一个无辜的孩子 什么也没做
只是对关闭他的足球学校表示抗议
我要你坦白
好吗
是他们引发的暴乱 不是我们
不是我弟弟
不是迈赫迪
他当时很害怕
他很害怕 想要逃走 承认吧
他想要从你引发的暴乱中逃走
承认吧
好吧 你说得对
是上面下的指令
别跟我说废话
迈赫迪只是在错误的时间出现在了错误的地方
那你为什么要追他
他们逼我的
他必须成为暴乱的牺牲品
什么
他们逼我的 我发誓
你必须要相信我
住手
没有人能被逼成为杀人犯
想想你做过的事情
我会带着一封坦白信回来
你要在上面签字
如果你不签
如果你拒绝
我会烧死你
- 不要 - 要的
我会活活烧死你
混蛋 你在哪儿
Blimey bastard, where are you?
当今的年轻人
喂
我是卡尔
It's Karl.
谁
聪明的卡尔 运动健将
Sensitive Karl, the sporty intellectual.
你好 我给你买了咖啡
Bonjour, I got you a cappuccino.
怎么没给亚当带一份
Maybe Adam will have one.
- 亚当 - 我借一下毛巾 行吗
- Adam ? - I borrowed a towel, if that's ok.
发生了什么事?
What is going on?
亚当昨天在这过夜
Adam stayed here last night.
我出去等着好了
I'll be outside.
你最好有正当的理由
This had better be good.
我没必要回答你
I don't have to answer to you.
她是我同事
She is my colleague.
- 所以呢? - 你是我儿子
- And? - You're my son.
我每天都得和她共事
I have to work with her every day,
你把事情搅得一塌糊涂
makes things just a tiny bit fucking difficult.
为什么不管什么事你都要来插一脚?
Why does it always have to be about you?
还是你嫉妒我?
Or are you jealous?
嫉妒你什么?
Of what?
还要我直说吗
That's what it is.
归根结底就是尊重二字
It's about respect is what it is.
那你倒是尊重我啊
Start showing some.
- 拜托你成熟一点 - 我一直很成熟
- Oh ! Grow up! - I did.
只是你从来没发现而已
You just never took any notice .
你在干什么?
刚刚做完一些东西
什么东西?
会让你自豪的东西
没有什么想和我说的吗?
等我做完了会告诉你的
好的 你继续吧
天啊
Oh God.
我迟到了 大事不好
I'm so late, it's not even funny.
厨房里面有咖啡还有一些杂七杂八的
Listen, there's coffee and shit in the kitchen,
你要什么自己拿
just grab whatever.
你什么都不知道
Do you know something.
你甚至都没问过我的名字
You never even asked me my name.
我是故意的
That's intentional.
如果我不知道你的名字
If I'm never told a name,
以后你就不会怪我忘了你
I can never be accused of forgetting it.
你不能那样做
You can't do that.
做什么?
Do what?
不管你们两个做了什么
Whatever it was you were doing together.
你们到底做了什么?
What was it you were doing together?
算了 不要回答
Don't answer that.
你到底想问什么?
What are you trying to ask me?
你是不是跟我儿子上床了?
Did you have sex with my son?
他成年了
He's 18.
我知道!
I know!
他有隐私权
He's entitled to a private life.
只有没有孩子的人
That's the sort of thing
才会说这种鬼话
that people who don't have kids say.
他是有权利
He is entitled to try and keep things
隐瞒父母
from his parents is what he is entitled to do.
但是现在他没能做到
and on this occasion he didn't manage it.
你是不是跟我儿子上床了?
Did you have sex with my son??
那我是不是也有权利...
Am I entitled to.......
回答我的问题
Did you have sex with my son ???
- 没有 - 好
- No - Good.
谁?
What?
那两个孩子要成为头条新闻了
The youth were meant to be front page
你没有听我说话
but you did not listen
没有 我在听 我只是不知道说什么
No I listened,  I just don't do requests..
出去
Go outside
我想让你看点东西
There is something I want you to see
你从这里怎么去上班?
How would you get to work from here?
- 我开我的赛车去 - 如果你是中产阶级
- I'd take my 4x4. - On an average wage
那怎么办 公车?
I don't know. Bus?
走过去
Walk it
走路
P4010
"P" 4 "O" 10.
什么东西? 公车号码还是什么?
What's that ? A bus route or something?
不 这是五氧化二磷
No, it's the correct molecular formula for
正确的分子公式
Phosphorus pentoxide
如果你把这个放在明天报纸的头版
For when you put that on tomorrow's front page
它将会成为爆炸性头条新闻
And it will be the front page
和她谈话很开心
We just had a nice little chat
她叫凯莉
Her name was Kelly.
是一名准记者
She was training to be a journalist.
她需要你的帮助 不过我应该早点告诉她的
She wanted your help. I should have warned her.
丹尼从来不主动发问
Danny doesn't do requests.
天啊
Name of God!
我知道这不是我的工作
不过大家对真理杀手都很感兴趣
比如他是谁 接下来打算做什么
我在听
我看了他放在网上的照片
其中一个人我认识
迈赫迪・谢尔菲
他死于抗议学校关闭而发生的一起暴乱
那个杀人凶手
根据在警察巡逻上发布的消息
是一名警察 叫劳伦特・德尔加多
劳伦特・德尔加多
他怎么了?
昨晚德尔加多的妻子报警说他失踪了
今早我打他的电话 他还没回来
无论如何非常感谢你
Thank you very much. Whatever it was.
他已经换了作案的国家 换了作案的手法
He has changed country, he has changed approach.
也就是说他从被压迫的青少年
Says he's moving from the oppressed youth
转移到压迫者
to the oppressors?
是的 分析角度不同但是道理是一样的
Yes, the same truth different angle.
我们认为真理杀手已绑架了劳伦特・德尔加多
我需要你手上迈赫迪・谢尔菲的所有资料
他去年死了
然后呢?
你要名单上法国青年的详细资料
对
我以为你的意思是还活着的那些
为什么?
你只要做好本职工作
那些假设都是浪费时间
如果德尔加多在真理杀手手上
If the TT has taken Delgado
为什么他还没有烧死他?
why hasn't he burned him ?
问得好
Good question.
那些闹事的孩子呢?
What about the kids from the riot?
谢尔菲家里在房地产正中心
The Cherfi family has a grocery shop
开了一家杂货店
right in the heart of the estate.
也许我们应该去那看看 那可是块风水宝地
Maybe we should get up there. It's as good a place as any.
怎么了?
What's the matter?
他总是告诉我们他的计划
He always tells us what he is planning.
他会打电话 发邮件
He makes calls, posts.
这次怎么没有?
Why not this time?
说不定我们先他一步
Maybe we're one step ahead.
我 劳伦特・德尔加多
承认杀死迈赫迪・谢尔菲...
这是我儿子雅辛
是关于劳伦特・德尔加多失踪的事
知道了
你认识劳伦特・德尔加多吗?
我知道他会下地狱的
你知道他在哪吗?
不知道 算他走运
请你走近些
过去吧
发生什么事了?
我做了什么吗?
我们问问题是为了你的安全
他今晚不能外出
凭什么? 我儿子想去哪就去哪
你可以搜我们俩的身 搜这个店
我们没什么好藏着掖着的
- 行 - 绝对没有
行了 手举起来
有股汽油味
Smells of petrol.
他抽烟吗?
不抽
等等 爱丽丝!
他又发布消息了
我马上回来
他把德尔加多交给了那群小孩
He is handing Delgado over to the kids.
领先一步也到此为止了
看看我们能从雅辛那知道什么
防暴警察正在接手
你为什么带着火柴?
又不犯法
有个恐怖分子在活烧人们
还把你弟弟放到了他网站上
而你无缘无故地带着火柴
这什么架势? 我被捕了吗?
你在协助调查
真的吗?
劳伦特・德尔加多在哪?
我不知道
我觉得你知道
就算我知道...
- 我凭什么告诉你? - 你满身汽油味
我在车库
所以弄得满手都是?
对
听着
迈赫迪他...
- 我们辜负了他 - 你们没辜负他
你们杀害了他
真理杀手手上的
This list.
这个名单
That TT has.
据说列着所有被警方虐待的人
With all those mistreated by the police, allegedly.
- 我们有吗? - 有
- Do we have one? - Yeah.
我们可以向CNDS要一份
We can request one from CNDS.
所有指控他们都记录在案
They have all allegations on file.
- 不过那是机密 对吧? - 当然
- It's classified though, right? - Of course.
在英国也是
Yeah, same in UK.
- 所以呢? - 他在炫耀
- So? - He's showing off.
证明只要他想要
Proving he can get any information he wants
机密信息也一样能拿到
even if that is classified.
是炫耀还是露了马脚?
Showing off or giving himself away?
他怎么拿到信息的?
How did he get hold of it?
我 劳伦特・德尔加多
承认杀死迈赫迪・谢尔菲...
那家伙临阵脱逃啦?
你口中的那家伙是我儿子
我就剩这个孩子了
唯一的一个
他前程似锦
他不该为我将做的事面临指控
起来
跪下来
你杀了我的孩子
我的宝贝儿子
给我一个不杀你的理由...
一个好理由
我说不出来